A loud eruption out of the draft room,
the Cardinals stick and pick at number
three. It's running back Jeremiah Love
out of Notre Dame. Right to my left,
general manager Monti Ossenfort got to
make that exciting, life-changing phone
call. I am Dani Soreck. Monti, you said
you can never take too many good players
in the draft. What made Jeremiah Love
the best player at three? Yeah, Dani, I
think really the the way he's been an
explosive playmaker for Notre Dame the
last two years. And not only just as a
runner, uh but also as a receiver. Um
his ability to put stress on the
defense,
um and score the ball from just about
anywhere. You we saw short, tough,
physical runs. We saw him uh break away
in space and make long, explosive runs.
And then really an underrated part of
his game is really his pass protection.
You don't see as many uh you don't see
many uh college running backs at all
come out and be as detailed as he is in
pass protection. So, his ability to be
on the field for all three downs just
really attracted us to him. The numbers
are impressive. Averaged almost seven
yards a carry each of the last two
seasons. Last year, 21 total touchdowns,
a Heisman finalist. You mentioned the
pass protection. What else do you like
most about Love's game that you don't
see on the stat sheet? Yeah, really. I
mean, I it's you see guys that are um
that are as fast as he is and explosive
as he is, but he does still get the
tough yards. He he churns out those, you
know, third and three, third and four
yard runs, finishes his runs. Um
sometimes you can see guys like him uh
choose the path of least resistance, go
out of bounds. So, you know, Jeremiah
does not like to go out of bounds. And
so, um and it's not surprising once you
get to know the kid and see what he's
about and his makeup, um you know, it's
it's not surprising that he plays the
way he does. Your years of scouting
experience, when it comes to running
backs who are successful, productive in
college, which traits most easily
transfer into the pros early on? Yeah,
it's really uh you know, the ability to
run with strength, balance, uh vision,
instincts, um you know, the the holes
that that are there in college, they get
a lot tighter in the NFL. And so, when
you see backs that are able to uh keep
their speed, keep their acceleration,
their quickness even on contact, um
those are guys that tend to translate
well to our level. It's a fine line of
best player available and position of
need. You have a full running backs room
right now. Where did Jeremiah Love fit
in that realm and where do you envision
his role becoming? Yeah, I mean, really
at this point Jeremiah's role will be
whatever he makes of it. And so, we'll
get him in here. His first job will be
learning this coaches, learning his
teammates, uh learning the new offensive
system, and then just to get out on the
field with his teammates and compete.
And it's it's it's it's amazing how many
times competition sorts itself out. Um
you know, Jeremiah brings a unique skill
set to the room uh that's different than
the other guys in our room. And there's
those things will all sort themselves
out. We'll put the players in the best
position to succeed and to help the
team.
I'm really excited to get him here to
carve out that role. Over the last few
years, you've taken a lot of pride in
making that life-changing phone call to
the player surrounded by their friends
and family. Once you got the right phone
number to get in contact with Love, what
was your message to him telling him he's
a Cardinal?
>> Yeah, it's just it's it's a surreal
moment, you know, I can't I can't
imagine how those those kids feel when
they get, you know, something that
they've worked their whole life for.
Um and just to feel uh feel them on the
phone and feel like a sense of
joy, relief, uh it all is mixed into
one. And so,
um just to be able to share that moment
with them uh knowing that their family
is there and and just the elation that
they must be feeling. Uh it's it's just
a really cool moment.
>> Character is a high value for you.
You've met with Love throughout this
process. What will fans soon learn about
Love and the type of person he is?
>> Yeah, he's a really impressive kid. I
mean, he's he's humble, uh his head's on
his shoulders the right way. Um he's
about the right stuff. It's team first.
He wants to do whatever he can do to
help the team. Uh I can't wait for you
guys to get a chance to meet him. Uh
he's a he's a really cool kid and and
we're just lucky to have it to add him
to our group.
>> Cardinals fans are very excited about
the new addition to this team.
Congratulations, Monti. Appreciate the
time. Cardinals fans, for more coverage
on Jeremiah Love as well as the rest of
the draft, stay locked in on
azcardinals.com. For Monti Ossenfort,
I'm Dani Soreck. Thanks so much for
tuning in.